BASED ON THE NOVEL "INFLUENZA"
BY HAN SANG-WOON
Corporal Jeon!
Shouldn't we do something about that?
Put that down!
The admin officer will give us hell
if you fire that.
But we're soldiers.
We have to do something!
I know. Just hold on a sec.
- I can shoot it.
- You can't!
I'm going to shoot it!
- Lower your rifle!
- How can I?
- We have to do something!
- Do not fire!
What do we do?
They're coming this way.
- They're coming toward us.
- I see that!
- In-ho!
- Yes?
- They're headed straight for us!
- Sir!
No!
They need to stop!
What is that? What the fuck?
Is it a terrorist attack?
What the heck was that?
What about the people down there?
- Damn it.
- Really?
- Sir!
- This is an emergency!
Hey.
We should go back, right?
This is a state of emergency.
If we're facing a state of emergency,
we should buy gas first
before returning to base.
- You just want the donuts, don't you?
- No, sir!
Okay, fine.
Let's get that gas and head back.
- Excuse us!
- Move!
- It's a state or emergency!
- Move it!
He popped up out of nowhere.
We're not even at a crosswalk.
Sir...
Do something about this.
Hey, don't give that to me!
Get that thing away from me!
Why did you do that?
Hold on a second.
Insurance...
I need to call the insurance...
Hey, are you okay?
He's still alive, right?
Damn it.
GOOD AFTERNOON BAKERY
Hurry, get out.
Me?
Why?
Seriously? We can't just leave him here.
Hurry up. Help me pull him out.
Just give me a second.
I need to call the insurance company.
Damn it.
- Hey, press the lobby button.
- Yes, sir.
Excuse me. Please hold the elevator.
Close it. Enemy aircraft, nine o'clock.
What the heck?
Damn it!
I'm sorry, sir.
We're screwed.
Did you see that plane crash?
Yes, we did.
Then you must know
we're in a state of emergency.
Shouldn't you return to base
instead of lounging around in the hotel?
Actually,
we're in the middle of a mission.
If so, shouldn't you be more discreet?
Your station here is classified intel.
But you're using the guest elevator
as if you want to be seen.
From what I've seen,
there is no sense of protocol.
Then, get our elevator fixed already.
This is stressful for us as well.
We can only make the call.
We're not repairmen.
Until then, shouldn't you use
the emergency stairs?
Has eating the hotel food made you soft?
I just can't believe
- how sluggish you all are.
- Hold on.
We only eat the hotel food
because you won't let us cook.
Of course.
What if there's a fire?
Who will take responsibility?
Do you think we're here
to play around with fire...
or something?
What's going on?
- Breathe.
- Central elevator two is down.
This is Arron Park speaking.
We're checking it now.
Please wait a moment.
Please take care of it
as swiftly as possible.
Let's avoid
causing each other discomfort...
by sticking to the protocol.
Damn you!
It's working again!
Thank goodness.
That was so scary.
Watch out!
Get away!
What's going on?
- Sir?
- Private Lee?
What is going on?
What the heck?
Hey, lady!
Please give me a hand!
Hey, red car! Help me pull him out!
You with the black hat and a corn dog!
Mr. Corn Dog! Help me!
- Go on and help her.
- Hurry.
Please help me!
What do you want me to do?
How did such a big accident happen?
You're Alex.
Aren't you Sung Tae-shik?
No, I'm not.
I'm sorry,
but I have an appointment to get to.
It's Alex, the CEO!
- It is him!
- The rich and famous Alex!
What? It's really Alex?
He's so good-looking!
Look at his butt!
- Alex, look here for the camera!
- Smile for the picture.
Let's see some teeth. Smile.
- Cheese!
- Show us those pearly whites!
Will you help me?
- Help her already.
- Please, hurry.
Fine. Okay.
I'm going to help her.
All right. I hear you.
- Pull him out.
- Yes, I'll help her out.
Please hurry.
I got it.
I will help her. Okay.
Let's put this down and help that guy.
Look! It's Alex!
What a hero!
You crazy bastard.
What are you doing? Get down!
What the heck?
What should I do?
Just ignore him and help this man.
- I'll get his torso. You grab his legs.
- Okay, I got it.
- Young-joo, what are you doing?
- One, two, three.
- Hey, mister. Get off!
- One, two...
- One, two, three.
- Young-joo, stop that!
You have to preserve
the scene of the accident!
This is Arron Park,
Chief Manager of Eden Hotel.
People are injured on the 53rd floor.
Please hurry.
Was he bitten by a dog?
If I may chime in,
that doesn't seem like a dog bite.
It looks more like a lion bit him.
- Get a closer look.
- Pardon?
Go on!
He is a guest!
My heart just dropped.
Do not lay a finger on him!
Help is on the way.
What the hell is going on here?
What's going on here?
I pinched myself
to see if this was a dream.
This isn't a dream.
It stinks.
What the...
- What's wrong with you?
- Hey, Private!
Are you okay?
What is that?
What the fuck is that?
What the heck!
Get up. Come on!
Stop it! Calm down!
What the hell is happening?
How is that possible?
Arron Park.
Arron Park!
- Flip him over.
- Okay.
One, two.
How is this possible? This makes no sense.
- What do you mean?
- He should be spewing blood.
- You're right.
- Hold on.
Hello? Sir?
Did you call 911?
Yes, I did.
Why aren't they coming?
Let's clear his airway.
I'll start CPR.
Right hand on top.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine...
Go easy! He just got hit by a car.
You're supposed to do it like this.
Here we go again.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight,
nine...
Wait, is that a hole in his body?
There's a hole in his body?
That's not right.
Sung Tae-shik just killed a man.
My goodness, how could he?
Oh, my god, Alex!
GB PER MILE INSURANCE COMPANY
Those fucking morons...
Didn't I tell them?
They should've just sat their asses down.
He just recklessly jumped in there.
But Alex was just trying to save him.
You call that saving?
Yeah, that's not...
It's a misunderstanding.
I didn't do this to him.
- Misunderstanding?
- No, we saw it.
- You did that to him.
- I didn't kill him.
Move aside. I'll save him.
- That's right.
- Step back.
- Move it.
- But I...
Now, I'll grab him here.
You grab him there.
Arron Park!
Fuck!
What do we do?
Help me!
You assaulted a civilian!
Does that look like a civilian to you?
Push!
It's working.
Where are you going? Hey!
Shit!
Private Lee, can I borrow that lighter
from your girlfriend?
Why?
Hurry, sir!
Damn it...
There's no time to explain!
What are you doing?
- Don't start a fire.
- I'm not playing with it!
Get me some strong alcohol now!
- Strong what?
- Okay, I got you.
Take over for me. I'll get it.
There are too many choices.
Hey, Arron Park!
- Which one's the strongest?
- What?
Which drink is the strongest?
RonDiaz 151!
Hang on!
It contains 75.5 percent alcohol.
Don't move! Damn it!
No!
Hurry up!
In-ho, catch!
Step aside, Private!
Do it now!
Private!
- Hurry. Help us.
- Grab his legs.
Damn it.
- One, two, three.
Hold on.
Be careful.
Maybe bring him this way...
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
You just hit someone with your car!
How can you just sit there...
What's wrong?
Are you hurt anywhere?
What the...
That's not good.
That seat is completely ruined.
Wait, what's that?
- Over there!
- What is it?
Get out now!
Hurry up. You're in danger!
Come on!
Someone, call 911!
Call 911!
Someone, call an ambulance!
There's been a car crash.
What is happening?
Oh, no. Mom!
Mommy...
EMERGENCY ALERT
WIDESPREAD ATTACKS
The aircraft has been shattered
beyond recognition.
While black smoke continues
to seep out through the debris,
desperate rescue operations are ongoing.
Hankuk Airline Flight KN 007
crashed into the middle of Gangnam
at 2:25 p.m. today.
Witnesses saw the plane
skim past a high-rise building
before suddenly changing course
and crashing into another building.
It lost one of its wings in the collision
before crashing down
in the middle of Seoul.
Local authorities announced
they will dispatch
the military, police, and firefighters
to search for survivors,
- but the outlook is bleak.
- Fuck, we're screwed.
We look forward to hearing
about swift rescue efforts
as Seoul deals with this terrible tragedy.
I was so worried because I thought
our base was being attacked.
But Corporal Jeon and I
were prepared to counterattack.
How dare you act
without the CO's permission?
What did I tell you?
Yes. I understand, sir.
What did he say?
Are we to be dispatched to the scene?
It seems the plane crash
is the least of our problems.
Pardon?
A state of national emergency
has been declared,
and martial law has been imposed.
Martial...
Martial law?
Yes, that's right.
Arm all units
and have them on a five-minute standby.
Yes, sir.
Sergeants Ahn and Yoo haven't returned
from their lunch downstairs, right?
I'll call them in.
Thank you.
Your call has been forwarded to...
DISABLE SPRINKLERS?
YES
SECURITY MANAGER KIM SEON-YONG
You've reached Arron Park.
Where are you? The 53rd floor
is a freaking mess right now.
Hey, light the lighter.
What did you say?
Are you kidding me?
Okay, it works.
I'll take that.
Then, just stay there. I'll come to you.
What did he say?
Tell us.
Everyone on his team
has been ripped apart.
What will you two do?
He's the only one I managed
to reach on the security team.
The whole building has been taken over.
Avoid the lower floors if you can.
If you turn right,
you'll see the west emergency stairs.
Can we take the elevator?
Stairs are safer in an emergency.
Okay. We'll return to our base, then.
We should, right?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
But what about this man of legend?
Don't mind me.
I have to wait for the rescue team anyway.
Hey, why don't you just come with us?
We may be sluggish and all,
but the military is
the safest option right now.
I am the chief manager here.
Pardon?
In these situations,
I need to stand my ground until the end.
Off you go!
By the way,
- what did you mean by "man of legend"?
- Pardon?
Is that my nickname?
It's nothing. Take care of yourself.
- He should be fine, right?
- He's dead meat.
I don't know, man. Let's head out.
What is wrong with you?
Get up!
That was my car!
What's wrong?
Seo Jin-wook!
Hey!
- Hey!
- Hold on. I'll get him.
Stay right there!
- Come on!
- Just come with us!
Come on already!
I'm not going anywhere.
My car is fucking wrecked!
Split up!
You go that way. I'll go this way!
What the...
What the fuck?
Alex!
Go that way! Run!
Run!
Damn it!
Move out of the way!
Where do we go?
What the heck is this?
Seriously!
Why is this door not closing?
What the fuck is going on?
Sir.
I think it's pretty serious.
Let's report back first.
Yes, sir.
1ST PLATOON DUTY ROSTER
Sung-gyu and Byung-joon, these bastards.
- Any word from Lee and Ra?
- Not yet, sir.
How long has it been?
It's been a bit over an hour.
Maybe I should go downstairs...
All units are to be
on a five-minute standby.
The squad commander can't leave.
Yes, sir.
Let's maintain our position
for a little longer.
Head to the barracks and be on standby.
Yes, sir.
En route to standby, sir.
Are you all right, sir?
Do you have a cigarette?
First Sergeant.
Yes?
You've experienced
battle firsthand, right?
Yes, sir. I've been deployed.
What about martial law?
It's my first time, sir.
Hey, are you okay?
Come here.
Hurry!
Kang Young-joo!
Where are you?
Hurry up!
Shit. Damn it.
Damn it...
That hurt.
Wait. Give me a sec.
What the hell is going on?
Private Lee, sir.
I hope our families are safe.
Wait. Where's my lighter?
Hey.
- Private Ra In-ho.
- Let's go.
- Let's head up.
- Yes, sir.
Damn it. We're fucked.
What do we do now?
The north.
Let's go to the north stairs.
Then, we need to walk through the hotel.
That's right.
It'll be filled with people.
Will we be okay?
Probably not.
We need to stay alert.
Let's go.
Wait!
- For fuck's sake!
- Wait.
One.
Two.
Three.
Damn it.
Last week,
a Kim Cheol's Salon opened up next door.
And this week, it's zombies?
It's a conspiracy
to bleed small businesses dry.
Damn it.
- Mom.
- Where are you?
I'm in Gangnam.
Did you go there to see Jae-yoon?
Why in the world would you go there?
Don't worry about me. I'll be home soon.
How could I not worry about you?
Hurry up and get home!
Damn it.
- But I'm right near his base.
- You're where?
Hold on a second.
That might actually be
the safest place right now.
They have soldiers with guns there.
- Go to Jae-yoon.
- Oh, Mom.
I'll figure it out.
Don't worry about me
and stay inside the house.
Call me as soon as you arrive.
Okay.
- Mom!
- Yes?
Don't leave the house.
Okay. Get going, Young-joo!
I'd be better off dead.
Why is this my cross to bear?
Oh, dear God, Buddha...
The phone is turned off.
After the tone, please leave a message.
Charges may apply.
SWEET JAE-YOON
MESSAGE
Jae-yoon, you're safe, right?
I'm right by the tower.
Call me when you see this.
I'll go to where you are.
What the heck?
- Who's there?
- It's you two!
What was that for?
What is with you?
Say something.
"Say something"? Like what?
Just say something
to convince me you're normal.
I am an artilleryman
in the First Air Defense Brigade--
Lower your voice.
Private Ra In-ho at your service.
My ID number is 25-0060778.
I have no idea when I'll be discharged.
And I'm his senior officer
who led him here.
Isn't that enough?
You're definitely not zombies, right?
We told you we're not. Jeez.
Get up.
Let me take a look.
Sorry about that.
Sorry.
That stings!
RIOTS BREAK OUT NATIONWIDE
Reports of civilian riots
-are flooding in nationwide.
- What is going on?
-What started out
- Is that real?
as small-scale riots in Seoul
have quickly escalated
- and spread across the country.
- Damn it.
The random attacks have plunged the nation
- into a war-like emergency crisis.
- Seriously?
First, a plane crashes
in the middle of Gangnam
and now, we have riots?
The Ministry of National Defense
- says military action is in discussion.
- Squad commander, we'll be okay, right?
It looks like utter chaos from up here.
- In some of the affected areas,
- Kyung-sik, turn it off.
- reports of opportunistic crime
- Yes, sir.
like sexual assault are also on the rise.
NAME: JEON HYUNG-BAE
POSITION: VULCAN GUNNER
Jeon Hyung-bae, Choi Chul-woo!
- Sir, yes, sir!
Pull yourselves together.
This is not a drill.
- Yes, sir.
Salute.
I'm sure you've seen the news on TV.
Truth be told,
we are not up against terrorism or war.
However, our national security
is still certainly at stake
and, you know...
It's...
Now, we...
Over to you.
It is our duty to prioritize air defense,
so we shall secure the roof.
But keep in mind that under martial law,
orders may be subject to change.
You will now all be armed with rifles.
- Sergeant Kim.
- Sergeant Kim Young-man, reporting.
FIREARMS
KIM YOUNG-MAN
Keep your dog tags safe
if you don't want to end up
as an unidentified body.
Why the fuck would you say that?
Corporal Jeon Hyung-bae.
Rifle number 237080.
Private Choi Chul-woo.
Rifle number 237031.
Private Hwang Kyung-sik.
Rifle number 237084.
Due to the risk of accidental discharge,
live ammo will be issued
when the situation escalates.
Okay, get the rest of your gear ready
and take your positions.
- Yes, sir.
This damn prick.
What a spoiled jerk.
Where is he hiding it?
I found it.
And the watch...
- Rolex...
- Hey, punk!
How can you steal at a time like this?
- I hope you get torn apart by zombies!
- Shit!
- Jin-wook!
- Unbelievable. Look at him run.
- Hey, Seo Jin-wook!
- Do you know him?
- Is he okay?
- I think so.
EMERGENCY PHONE
Hey.
That doesn't work.
What?
Would I be here if it worked?
Then, by chance, do you have
a cell phone I can borrow?
I need to make an important call.
Would I be here if I did?
Then, by chance,
is there a landline on this floor?
Well...
There is one by the restaurant counter.
Okay.
But it's crawling with zombies.
PAINT THINNER
SANITIZER
- Private Lee, sir.
- Yeah?
Permission to speak, sir?
What is it now?
I'd like to propose an idea.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Private Ra In-ho.
Where did everyone go?
I believe that works in our favor.
Hey.
Look over there.
- What?
- Where?
- Sir?
- No, hold up.
Where did he go?
Wait, that guy is...
He's not responding, sir.
Don't come any closer.
Wait!
Ra In-ho!
- Soo-jeong, stand up.
- His head...
Help her up.
Yes, sir.
Are you okay, Soo-jeong?
Are Sung-gyu and Byung-joon
still out of comms?
Yes, sir.
And the ones who went to buy gas
haven't returned?
No, sir. They took my card,
but I haven't received a payment alert.
That means they're
still on their way to the gas station,
or they're stuck
somewhere in the building.
By the smallest chance,
if the worst-case scenario happens...
We will make sure to collect their bodies.
Sergeant Kim.
Yes, sir.
You and I will go down together
to search and assess the situation.
Are you afraid?
No, sir. I understand, sir.
- Damn it.
- Oh, no.
Fuck, that scared me.
That's mine.
Hey, can you pick that up for me?
Is your head okay?
No, it still hurts.
Let's go, Young-joo.
- But...
- Yeah?
Do you think going to a police station
will do us any good?
It's common sense to go
to the nearest station at times like this.
Then, I'll follow you there
before heading over to A Tower.
How do you plan to get there all alone?
I'll figure it out. Don't worry about me.
Forget it.
Let's just get going.
You should come with us.
- No. I can't leave my shop.
- That damn bastard.
In case we don't see each other again,
take care of yourself.
You too.
What are you doing, Young-joo?
Hurry up. We don't have time.
He's definitely not worth your time.
Go and find your boyfriend.
- Thanks for everything.
- No problem.
Fuck!
That asshole took my phone.
- Goodbye.
- He's dead if I ever see him again.
Hurry up already.
- Hey.
- Yes?
I don't think anyone's here.
But we must stay vigilant.
In zombie movies,
this is when something pops out.
Do you hear that?
They're zombie sounds!
This way! We need to go this way!
- This way.
- Hurry up.
- Chef Jung?
- Chef Jung!
Chef Jung!
Private Lee Jae-yoon.
Is it dinnertime already?
Are you hurt anywhere?
I feel like I might be soon.
These glass doors
won't hold for much longer!
Do something!
Hold on! Let me think!